so Charles Eisenstein released a few
videos over the last few weeks on
masculinity and femininity and I love
99% of what that man says and I don't
like that when anyone talks at masculine
femininity if anyone's going to I feel
like he's probably a good one to do it
but he said the thing that they all say
that is which is that in order to have
sexual charge you need to have a
masculine and feminine polarity that
were batteries for magnets you need to
have one or the other that's where the
polarity comes from and part of me
believed that for decades it's what I
learned from Ken Wilbur's work and when
I've learned from David data and it's
not true if you have to try to be the
positive and someone else to try to be
the negative in order to create a
polarity that is nowhere near as much
charge and energy as just being your
authentic self and finding someone that
is also being authentic and do you match
or not is there sexual chemistry instead
of trying to make there be sexual
chemistry if there isn't it's because
one of us is being the wrong thing one
of us isn't masculine enough one of us
isn't feminine enough or you don't have
sexual chemistry because that sexual
chemistry does actually dissipate
actually dissipates over time whereas
being your authentic self and constantly
growing you know you're gonna
continually change and so they're gonna
continually change if what you have to
do is try to be masculine or try to be
feminine you're not doing it right I
just don't understand why you would want
to try to be something new or not if you
are feminine if you are masculine
independent of what your body is you're
doing it right do you want to play with
dolls do you want to wrestle do you want
to wear pink do you want to wear blue
none of those things are reliant they're
highly correlated but not reliant on
what your body looks like not reliant on
what your sex or gender are and so for
masculine feminine into back into gender
and sex is like where it definitely
starts to break for me because if you
have to try to be masculine
you're it's broken why do you have to
try to be it you either are it or you're
not if you are broken as a man because
they're not masculine enough what does
that mean especially on the masculine
side which is thought of as as
intelligent and brave it's neither
intelligent or brave to try to be
something you're not just to fit into
society it doesn't bring you happiness
so it's not intelligent and it's not out
of out of alignment of what everyone
else is doing so it doesn't really take
bravery and so when all of society says
to a little boy you're supposed to be
masculine and he's feminine that is
bravery
it would not be bravery for that little
masculine boy to pretend to be feminine
or for the little feminine boy tend to
be masculine
it's whatever naturally arises in you so
to raise generations of children to be
who they are
including embracing all of their
masculine characteristics all of their
feminine characteristics are they
characteristics they want to have are
they things they want to pursue not you
have to go in just this sport because
you're a boy or you have to go into this
sport because you're a girl or this art
because you're a girl do you want to do
it does it inspire you does it feel good
to be there then do it otherwise don't
check in on yourself not whether it fits
under the masculine or feminine umbrella
and that is part of my life's mission
helping people figure out helping me
figure out my most authentic self and
constantly figure out where I'm trying
to be something for a society and where
I'm allowing something to merge that's
uniquely mine and I want the uniquely
mine part F the society part and I want
other people to get on that path because
I know how much happiness and
authenticity is there and I know we can
unlock together when a tiny handful of
us start doing that then we call them
the masses and more and more of us start
doing that that is where the power lies
and you can't co-opt that not in the
same way you can co-op masculinity
femininity the left and the right
because when you don't have a buy-in
when it's about what naturally emerges
from inside of you even if it's a binary
it doesn't matter masculine feminine
male/female boy-girl no no matters who
are you and can you show up as your best
self and when you don't can we forgive
you
and can we love each other in that and
can we help each other become the best
versions of ourselves and be the best
version of our own self without having
an outside metric that we are either
failing to live up to
or feel superior because we've managed
to when other people have it thank you
see you next time